<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>LEE_SPEAK</title><link>https://leespeak.me/gaming/</link><description>Recent content on LEE_SPEAK</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>lee@liamdouglas.com (Liam McKenna)</managingEditor><webMaster>lee@liamdouglas.com (Liam McKenna)</webMaster><copyright>© 2025 Liam McKenna</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leespeak.me/gaming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Will Copper Disrupt the Progression of Minecraft?</title><link>https://leespeak.me/gaming/copper_tools/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>lee@liamdouglas.com (Liam McKenna)</author><guid>https://leespeak.me/gaming/copper_tools/</guid><description>Today I opened my YouTube to find a new minecraft update announcement at the top of my recommended. Ironically, I had another topic I planned on writing about today that was also Minecraft-related, but that will have to wait.
In their latest update video, Mojang has given copper a handful of new use cases. For the purposes of this discussion, the one standout announcement is that of copper tools and armor.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[


<img
  src="/images/gaming/copper_tools.jpeg"
  style="
    display: inline-block;
    vertical-align: top;
    box-sizing: border-box;
    margin: 0;
    padding: 0;
    border: none;
    box-shadow: none;
    
      transform: scale(1);
      transform-origin: top left;
    
  "
/>

<p>Today I opened my YouTube to find a new minecraft update announcement at the top of my recommended.
Ironically, I had another topic I planned on writing about today that was also Minecraft-related, but that will have to wait.</p>
<p>In their <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=542rY0DQHIM">latest update video</a>, Mojang has given copper a handful of new use cases.
For the purposes of this discussion, the one standout announcement is that of <strong>copper tools and armor</strong>.</p>
<p>There&rsquo;s an obvious discussion to be had here. Where exactly do I start, though? Minecraft&rsquo;s traditional progression system:</p>



<img
  src="/images/gaming/progression%201.png"
  style="
    display: inline-block;
    vertical-align: top;
    box-sizing: border-box;
    margin: 0;
    padding: 0;
    border: none;
    box-shadow: none;
    
      transform: scale(1);
      transform-origin: top left;
    
  "
/>

<p>Wood -&gt; Stone -&gt; Iron -&gt; Diamond</p>
<p>got <em>extended</em> with the introduction of</p>



<img
  src="/images/gaming/progression%202.png"
  style="
    display: inline-block;
    vertical-align: top;
    box-sizing: border-box;
    margin: 0;
    padding: 0;
    border: none;
    box-shadow: none;
    
      transform: scale(1);
      transform-origin: top left;
    
  "
/>

<p>Wood -&gt; Stone -&gt; Iron -&gt; Diamond <strong>-&gt; Netherite</strong></p>
<p>five years and one week ago, and has largely been seen as a successful endeavor. This came in spite of immediate discourse of eroding
tradition and arguing sacrilege for making an ore more powerful than diamond, because, well, <strong>it&rsquo;s diamond!</strong> You can&rsquo;t do that!</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m aware of how those takes aged. I&rsquo;m not explicitly rejecting copper&rsquo;s new role, I&rsquo;m more questioning it&rsquo;s potential impact, because
denouncing change for fear of cultural or traditional impact isn&rsquo;t exactly productive. At the time, I think it was right to point out the lack
of direct post-game progression to make use of netherite, because that&rsquo;s exactly what we ended up with in following updates (the warden, tricky trials, etc.).</p>
<p>So what happens when the new ore slots squarely <em>within</em> the existing progression?</p>



<img
  src="/images/gaming/progression%203.png"
  style="
    display: inline-block;
    vertical-align: top;
    box-sizing: border-box;
    margin: 0;
    padding: 0;
    border: none;
    box-shadow: none;
    
      transform: scale(1);
      transform-origin: top left;
    
  "
/>

<p>Wood -&gt; Stone <strong>-&gt; Copper -&gt;</strong> Iron -&gt; Diamond -&gt; Netherite</p>
<p>Honestly, probably not much, but it may depend on the level of player you are. I&rsquo;d wager seasoned players get to iron well within the first hour of starting a world,
so was there really a gap to address? There may be, and time will tell, but I doubt many people were pining Mojang to close the gap between stone and iron. The issue
is more so that copper is useless, which isn&rsquo;t a strong case for effectively diluting the very solid pace of progression Minecraft&rsquo;s ore system has demonstrably proven.</p>
<p>In a way, it feels like they&rsquo;re backtracking. For all intents and purposes, if Mojang had strong conviction that copper&rsquo;s purpose was, at least partially, that of an ore for progression,
they wouldn&rsquo;t have waited four years to give them such a role. Rewatching the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DBvZ2Iqmm3M">Caves &amp; Cliffs First Look</a>, Vanilla Minecraft Game Director
Agnes Larsson states:</p>
<p>&ldquo;Yes, I think I got inspired by the pretty copper roofs in Stockholm, and they are all green because we have so many old buildings there. We actually added
that mechanic to Minecraft&hellip; I think it&rsquo;s so cool because it actually adds history to Minecraft.&rdquo;</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s safe to say that copper was always positioned as a building ore, but now Mojang feels the need to justify the sheer amount of it you find within caves by transitioning it&rsquo;s role
to one of more general purpose, à la iron or gold. A similar thing happened with Lapis quite some time ago, albeit to a far lesser extent.</p>
<p>Lapis didn&rsquo;t get armor or tools, but it did see the entire enchantment system reworked alongside it. That panned out well, so this very well may too.
I&rsquo;m just struggling to find the merit in this specific use case for copper. It feels like Mojang is casually toying with one of Minecraft&rsquo;s most tried strengths in an attempt to justify a past
miscalculation.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Mojang Theory</title><link>https://leespeak.me/gaming/mojang/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>lee@liamdouglas.com (Liam McKenna)</author><guid>https://leespeak.me/gaming/mojang/</guid><description>Like many of those who grew up on Minecraft, I&amp;rsquo;ve often struggled to understand its developer&amp;rsquo;s philosophy when it comes to game updates. Like, I get it, they don&amp;rsquo;t want to change the game too much and risk undermining the core identity of the game, but there&amp;rsquo;s so much that notion alone doesn&amp;rsquo;t account for.
It&amp;rsquo;s bullshit to begin with &amp;ndash; I mean in practice, Mojang has done plenty to rip away the core of Minecraft as an experience.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Like many of those who grew up on Minecraft, I&rsquo;ve often struggled to understand its developer&rsquo;s philosophy
when it comes to game updates. Like, I get it, they don&rsquo;t want to change the game too much and risk undermining
the core identity of the game, but there&rsquo;s so much that notion alone doesn&rsquo;t account for.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s bullshit to begin with &ndash; I mean in practice, Mojang has done plenty to rip away the core of Minecraft as
an experience. The game was built on dynamic systems and, in the beginning, had its identity entrenched in
multifaceted mechanics and items. At some point we started getting a slew of updates with one-off ideas that
failed to contribute to the greater dynamic gameplay of the game&rsquo;s foundation.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Sure, let&rsquo;s add a mob called the sniffer that only has use for a brand new entirely superficial fossil digging
mechanic. For the <em>lore</em>.&rdquo;</p>
<p>I can&rsquo;t honestly tell how much mojang cares about maintaining the game&rsquo;s identity. If that&rsquo;s what they&rsquo;re going for,
they&rsquo;re not doing a very good job.</p>
<p>Regardless, the game has bugs that haven&rsquo;t been addressed for over a decade (see <a href="https://bugs-legacy.mojang.com/browse/MC-1794?attachmentSortBy=fileName&amp;utm_source=chatgpt.com">item stitching</a>, for example).</p>



<img
  src="/images/gaming/item_stitching.png"
  style="
    display: inline-block;
    vertical-align: top;
    box-sizing: border-box;
    margin: 0;
    padding: 0;
    border: none;
    box-shadow: none;
    
      transform: scale(1);
      transform-origin: top left;
    
  "
/>

<p>Thankfully there are an endless number of mods that can account for mojang&rsquo;s inaction. And this is where it hit me
&ndash; does Mojang not see bugs as issues so long as someone in the community fixes it for them? Even further, does this
extend to actual game features? I mean, surely overhauls like sodium and optifine takes the onus off them to optimize
their game.</p>
<p>So here goes the theory: <strong>Mojang does not care to do any work that has not already been done for them.</strong> If a mod has
done so, then their hands are clean. They don&rsquo;t even need to implement it themselves! Just quietly let each unsatisfied
player shuffle over to fabric and forge and figure it out themselves. It&rsquo;s genius, really.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>