<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>LEE_SPEAK</title><link>https://leespeak.me/music/</link><description>Recent content on LEE_SPEAK</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>lee@liamdouglas.com (Liam McKenna)</managingEditor><webMaster>lee@liamdouglas.com (Liam McKenna)</webMaster><copyright>© 2025 Liam McKenna</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leespeak.me/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Notes and Lessons from Vanisher, Horizon Scraper</title><link>https://leespeak.me/music/notes_from_vanisher/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>lee@liamdouglas.com (Liam McKenna)</author><guid>https://leespeak.me/music/notes_from_vanisher/</guid><description/><content:encoded></content:encoded></item><item><title>Some Scattered Thoughts on My Favorite Piece of Art</title><link>https://leespeak.me/music/idmthy_review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>lee@liamdouglas.com (Liam McKenna)</author><guid>https://leespeak.me/music/idmthy_review/</guid><description>I truly doubt I’ll ever find the words to properly describe how this album makes me feel, but I’m going to try anyway.
Death is scary, comforting, and inevitable. Its arrival is not supposed to be up to us, and that unpredictability is something that innately terrorizes us all. Therein lies this unique solace in the temptation of suicide: removing the uncertainty of the when and the how by freely deciding so for yourself.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[


<img
  src="/images/music/idmthy_cover.jpg"
  style="
    display: inline-block;
    vertical-align: top;
    box-sizing: border-box;
    margin: 0;
    padding: 0;
    border: none;
    box-shadow: none;
    
      transform: scale(1);
      transform-origin: top left;
    
  "
/>

<p>I truly doubt I’ll ever find the words to properly describe how this album makes me feel, but I’m going to try anyway.</p>
<p>Death is scary, comforting, and inevitable. Its arrival is not supposed to be up to us, and that unpredictability is something that innately terrorizes us all. Therein lies this unique solace in the temptation of suicide: removing the uncertainty of the when and the how by freely deciding so for yourself. But nothing is free—the relief found in suicidal ideation is offset by the paralyzing fear of regret. In one way or another, we are haunted.</p>
<p>The cold, delicate and debilitating emotions at the core of this album’s premise demand to be taken seriously. There’s no room for contrivance or cliché here, which makes Quadeca’s sincerity and sensitivity all the more valuable. I’m no doubt sounding pretentious when I put it this way, but art like this saves people; it saved me.</p>
<p>I Didn’t Mean to Haunt You is special. It’s special to me, obviously, but that’s not what I’m getting at. In conception and ambition, in composition and articulation, in cogency and authenticity—in totality, it is special. This album deserves to be heard, and deserves to be remembered.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>