<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>LEE_SPEAK</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/miscellaneous/</link>
    <description>Recent content on LEE_SPEAK</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>lee@liamdouglas.com (Liam McKenna)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>lee@liamdouglas.com (Liam McKenna)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2025 Liam McKenna</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/miscellaneous/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Honesty</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/miscellaneous/honesty/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>lee@liamdouglas.com (Liam McKenna)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/miscellaneous/honesty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m honest. I’ve always been honest. Bordering on an open book, at times I think I’m too honest. This being publicly accessible is probably a testament to that. This is what I’ve always told myself and always believed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, I’m underhanded. And cunning. Not in some sociopathic, badass manipulator way. Like, subtly, because I’m unconfident in doing things the proper way. I’d rather take a bunch of small invisible steps to get what I want than to just do the obvious single move.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m honest. I’ve always been honest. Bordering on an open book, at times I think I’m too honest. This being publicly accessible is probably a testament to that. This is what I’ve always told myself and always believed.</p>
<p>At the same time, I’m underhanded. And cunning. Not in some sociopathic, badass manipulator way. Like, subtly, because I’m unconfident in doing things the proper way. I’d rather take a bunch of small invisible steps to get what I want than to just do the obvious single move.</p>
<p>In that way, I’m dishonest. I’m honest with my words and dishonest with my actions. I think people would hesitate to call it outright dishonesty but to me that’s what it is. My goals aren’t perverse or out of the ordinary but going about them in such obfuscated and obtuse ways makes me feel like I’m doing something wrong—probably because I am. I don’t want that to remain the case.</p>
<p>Being honest means being direct with yourself, and with others, in what you want. If you want something, go get it. Not in some sneaky, conniving way, but through forthright action. Don’t save face. Stop worrying about failure or embarrassment. Deal with that when it happens because it’s inevitable, no matter how hard you try and avoid it. If you want to say something then use your voice even when it feels impossible. There’s always a way, and most of the time the true solution is exponentially simpler than the roundabout way you concocted through your hours of mental pacing.</p>
<p>Just go for it, man.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kyoto, Night 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/miscellaneous/kyoto_night_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>lee@liamdouglas.com (Liam McKenna)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/miscellaneous/kyoto_night_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2025 &lt;br&gt;
1 A.M. &lt;br&gt;
On the bus exiting the airport &lt;br&gt;
In a foreign country &lt;br&gt;
Surrounded by strangers &lt;br&gt;
I have found a familiar feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2020 &lt;br&gt;
1 A.M. &lt;br&gt;
Walking along a hiking trail &lt;br&gt;
In a foreign state &lt;br&gt;
Surrounded by strangers &lt;br&gt;
It’s not a bad feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s not to say it’s pure bliss, but it is exhilarating. &lt;br&gt;
And guttural. &lt;br&gt;
Nervewracking. &lt;br&gt;
Such a unique feeling to happen all but a few times in my life. It’s a feeling of uncertainty and hope that occupies my mental. I’m much more composed than I was five years ago, but it’s not often a new chapter in life begins. When it does, you feel it. This time, things read more like a footnote or a side story. Nonetheless, I am surrounded by strangers with whom I will soon enough, assuredly, grow close. It’s all hitting me at once now that I’m finally here. &lt;br&gt;
What an exciting feeling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>2025 <br>
1 A.M. <br>
On the bus exiting the airport <br>
In a foreign country <br>
Surrounded by strangers <br>
I have found a familiar feeling.</p>
<p>2020 <br>
1 A.M. <br>
Walking along a hiking trail <br>
In a foreign state <br>
Surrounded by strangers <br>
It’s not a bad feeling.</p>
<p>That’s not to say it’s pure bliss, but it is exhilarating. <br>
And guttural. <br>
Nervewracking. <br>
Such a unique feeling to happen all but a few times in my life. It’s a feeling of uncertainty and hope that occupies my mental. I’m much more composed than I was five years ago, but it’s not often a new chapter in life begins. When it does, you feel it. This time, things read more like a footnote or a side story. Nonetheless, I am surrounded by strangers with whom I will soon enough, assuredly, grow close. It’s all hitting me at once now that I’m finally here. <br>
What an exciting feeling.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Every Year We Go to Michigan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/miscellaneous/every_year/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>lee@liamdouglas.com (Liam McKenna)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/miscellaneous/every_year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every year we go to Michigan. We&amp;rsquo;re either celebrating the 4th, a handful of birthdays, or both. It&amp;rsquo;s always in July so it serves as a good checkpoint in my recent years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In July of 2023, I was at the lowest point of my entire life. Graduation was looming with my post-education future in complete fog. I was in the dead middle of an
internship doing work I despised, hundred of miles away from home. Internally, I was paralyzed. Stuck in place by magnetic forces of suicidal trepidation and ideation, I feared death, but I feared the future just as much. My aunt and uncle invited me to spend the 4th with them and offered to take my cousins and me to the beach. If I recall, I was hesitant, allowing that paralysis to speak on my behalf. They were my only family in a country mile though, so as strong as those forces were, I knew better than to avoid family.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every year we go to Michigan. We&rsquo;re either celebrating the 4th, a handful of birthdays, or both. It&rsquo;s always in July so it serves as a good checkpoint in my recent years.</p>
<p>In July of 2023, I was at the lowest point of my entire life. Graduation was looming with my post-education future in complete fog. I was in the dead middle of an
internship doing work I despised, hundred of miles away from home. Internally, I was paralyzed. Stuck in place by magnetic forces of suicidal trepidation and ideation, I feared death, but I feared the future just as much. My aunt and uncle invited me to spend the 4th with them and offered to take my cousins and me to the beach. If I recall, I was hesitant, allowing that paralysis to speak on my behalf. They were my only family in a country mile though, so as strong as those forces were, I knew better than to avoid family.</p>
<p>It was a fun weekend. I probably needed it more than I let on, though my Uncle saw through any mask I tried to wear. We talked for a long time, and while I don&rsquo;t remember everything that was said, one bit stuck with me. I can&rsquo;t give an exact quote, but it went something along the lines of the following:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Life-long happiness isn&rsquo;t attainable. I&rsquo;ve found happiness in fleeting moments, but in my day to day, I&rsquo;m not happy. I&rsquo;m content with my life, but I&rsquo;m not happy, and I don&rsquo;t expect to be.</p></blockquote>
<p>I think in the moment, I didn&rsquo;t want to believe him. Even still, there&rsquo;s a part of me that just refuses to let such a hope die. But if I had to guess, he&rsquo;s probably right. In that case, I hope to one day be content with my life. I don&rsquo;t want to keep moving the goalpost down the field, expecting the next milestone in my life to finally be the one to do it. I want to learn to be content with my life right now, in my last moments, and at every point in-between.</p>
<p>Moving forward a year to July of 2024, I was in a radically different position in life. Now knowing concretely the next two years of my life to be spent in graduate school, all the while surrounded by the close friends I&rsquo;d made, my gaze was towards the sky. This time the whole extended family was here, and with nothing weighing me down, I could appreciate that time with my family to the fullest.</p>
<p>Even still, turning 22, I was once again afraid of losing what I had in that current moment. I&rsquo;d always expected life to flow in waves, and at least in my adulthood, it has. Good times are always eventually succeeded by darker ones, and back it goes to the median. The amplitudes, periods, and frequencies of such waves vary greatly, but what comes up always comes down&mdash;and come down things certainly did.</p>
<p>This year I find myself turning 23. In many regards, I feel right in between the extremes of the last two years, but my year thus far has largely mimicked the former. Life took its turn as quick as Winter turned to Spring, and I&rsquo;ve been desparately fighting for balance the whole year. I trust that things are trending upwards.</p>
<p>By the start of the Fall semester, I will have new horizons to look towards. I&rsquo;m leaving for Japan in September, so I want to spend as much time as possible with my friends and family in the coming weeks. After my arrival, I only have five more months until I close this chapter of my life. I want to be prepared for whatever awaits me, but I don&rsquo;t think I even know what exactly that means. No doubt, I will find out in due time.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calm Winds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/miscellaneous/calm_winds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>lee@liamdouglas.com (Liam McKenna)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/miscellaneous/calm_winds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Calm winds &lt;br&gt;
do little to obscure &lt;br&gt;
do little to drown out &lt;br&gt;
the invasive species seizing my attention &lt;br&gt;
but it can still pacify the chaos &lt;br&gt;
it uses alternative methods &lt;br&gt;
slowly, inconspicuously, yet unmistakibly making headway &lt;br&gt;
directing us, fulfilling the natural order &lt;br&gt;
the will of the universe &lt;br&gt;
one musn&amp;rsquo;t attempt to decipher a destination &lt;br&gt;
you&amp;rsquo;ll never be faster than the waves of light that color our existence &lt;br&gt;
but peace can be found &lt;br&gt;
in acceptance &lt;br&gt;
in appreciation &lt;br&gt;
for the priceless opportunity &lt;br&gt;
to feel those calm winds&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Calm winds <br>
do little to obscure <br>
do little to drown out <br>
the invasive species seizing my attention <br>
but it can still pacify the chaos <br>
it uses alternative methods <br>
slowly, inconspicuously, yet unmistakibly making headway <br>
directing us, fulfilling the natural order <br>
the will of the universe <br>
one musn&rsquo;t attempt to decipher a destination <br>
you&rsquo;ll never be faster than the waves of light that color our existence <br>
but peace can be found <br>
in acceptance <br>
in appreciation <br>
for the priceless opportunity <br>
to feel those calm winds</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
